Finding Aid for the Buddy Collette papers LSC.2458
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 6: Audio, Audiovisual, and Digital Materials, 464 audiovisual carriers (112 open-reel audiotapes, 267 audiocassettes, 85 videocassettes); 24 born-digital carriers (21 optical discs, 3 DATs)
  - Sub-Series 6.2: Cassette-Based Media
    - Sub-Sub-Series 6.2.1: Compact Audio Cassettes
      - Harlem Nights Pre Record (Box 40)
      - Heather DeHayward (Box 40)
      - Heather DeHayward, F. Collet, R. Simon, S. Ferguson (Box 40)
      - Hunt and Peck Collette, Performed by Buddy Collette with the LMU Jazz Ensemble (Box 40)
      - Institute for Educators, Music Center, B. Colette, Ellington Music, 1995 July 11 (Box 40)
      - Interview B.C. and Steve, 1989 (Box 40)
      - Interview B. Collette and Paul Bullock, 1981 August (Box 40)
      - Interview, B. Collette and Paul Bullock, 1981 September 3 (Box 40)
      - Interview Bill Lewis, Sharon Grane, B.C. (Box 40)
      - Interview Buddy, 1991 January 11 (Box 40)
      - Interview Leonard Feather, B. Collette (Box 40)
      - Interview #1, B. Collette and B. Cox, 1983 (Box 40)
      - Interview #2, Buddy Banks, Dudley Brooks, Buddy Collette, 1988 January (Box 40)
      - Interviews, B. Collette and Bob Stone, 1982 September (Box 40)
      - Interview with Buddy Collette with Howard Lucraft (Box 40)
      - Interview w/Gifford, 1987 May (Box 40)
      - Interview w/ Karen Lansky, 1989 June 15 (Box 40)
      - James Earl Jones (Roots) (Box 40)
      - James Newton and friends (Box 40)
      - James Newton, 1981 (Box 40)
      - James Van Buren, Hurry Up and Slow Down! (Box 40)
      - Jammin' At Verdi - Mix 1 (Box 40)
      - The Jane Getz Trio, Live in Las Vegas, Featuring Buddy Collette (Box 40)
      - Jazz at Acton, B. Collette, 1976 (Box 40)
      - Jazz at Acton #2, B. Collette (Box 40)
      - Jazz Best, 20 Immortal Jazz Standards (Box 40)
      - Jazz", Candoli, Collette, Guaraldi, Vinegar, Levey, Crown Records - CST 190, 1960 February 3 (Box 40)
      - Jazz Profiles, Collette (Box 40)
      - Jean Deacour Aud, B. Colette and Llew Matthews, 1980 (Box 40)
      - Jerome Memorial, 2000 September 10 (Box 40)
      - Jerome Memorial, 2000 September 10 (Box 40)
      - Jill Thornbury Interview PT 3 and 4 (Box 40)
      - Joe #8 90m (Box 40)
      - Joe #2 90m (Box 40)
      - Johnson and Kai and Brubeck / Golson B-Band (Box 40)
      - John Stephens Andr (Box 40)
      - John Swan; Jazz Trumpet Excerpts (Box 40)
      - Keith Jarrett "In the Light" (Box 40)
      - KPFK B.C. Interview, Jeanne Poole (Box 40)
      - KPFK, Buddy Collette, Eric Dolphy, 1987 June 19 (Box 40)
      - KPFK Interview, B. Collette and Jeanne Poole, 1968 (Box 40)
      - La Jolla, Buddy, Cheathams, Mike, Red, 1982 May 1 (Box 40)
      - L.A. Press Club, 1981 August 1 (Box 40)
      - LA Sax Giants, Hwd Bowl, Playboy Festival, 1993 June 12 (Box 40)
      - LA's Talk, R. Wyatt, R. Callender, B. Woodman, J. Kolson, B. Collette, 1991 (Box 40)
      - Las Vegas, B. Colette, G. Wiggins, D. MacDonald, 1990 December 3 (Box 40)
      - L. Feather and B. Colette, Music (Box 40)
      - The Links Cotillion, Belle of the Ball, The Night is Young, 1991 (Box 40)
      - Lionel - Body and Soul (Box 40)
      - "Little Band Big Jazz" C. Condoli, B. Collette, 1960 (Box 40)
      - L. Matthews, B. Bryant, 1982 (Box 40)
      - Magali - Jazz by the Bay (Box 40)
      - Magali - Jazz by the Bay (Box 40)
      - Magali - Jazz by the Bay (Box 40)
      - Magali - Jazz by the Bay (Box 40)
      - Mama (french song) (Box 40)
      - Manu Dubango Makossa Man and Soul Makossa (Box 40)
      - M. Ellington, Santa Barbara, CA, 1982 (Box 40)
      - M. Ellington Santa Barbara, CA, 1982 (Box 40)
      - Merer Ellington, Santa Barbara, CA, 1982 (Box 40)
      - Mike Cain Piano, (818) 760-4283 (Box 40)
      - Miles Davis, I Like Jazz: The Essence of Miles Davis (Box 40)
      - Mingus, Mingus, Mingus (Box 40)
      - Mom's Church, Pop's Speech, Birthday Dinner, 1979; 1981 (Box 40)
      - Mona Orbeck, Once Again (Box 40)
      - Monterey Jazz Festival, 1978 (Box 40)
      - More Bruce Brown Songs (Box 40)
      - Mulberry St., B.C., 1981 September (Box 40)
      - Museum Concert, 1984 April 8 (Box 40)
      - Museum ConcertMonorail (Box 40)
      - Music for Dolphy Performances (Box 40)
      - New Music for College Bands (Box 40)
      - Norvo - Collette (Box 40)
      - No Sound, 1971 (Box 40)
      - NPR Central Avenue Sounds, Collette, Isoardi and Brooks, 1999 August 31-September 1 (Box 40)
      - #10 Monterey Jazz Post, 1978 September 17 (Box 40)
      - #2 (Box 40)
      - 1: Festival in Black, Harold Land Quintet, 2: Festival in Black, Bobby Bryant, 1972 August 5 (Box 40)
      - "The Over The Hill Gang" Copy (Box 40)
      - P. Faith 1975 Sax, Invitation B. Colette (Box 40)
      - Pierre Delaney's Secret Pleasures (Box 40)
      - Play Boy Festival, The Sax Giants, 1993 (Box 40)
      - Polynesia, Buddy Collette (Box 40)
      - Portrait of a Silk Thread (Box 40)
      - Portrait of a Silk Thread, Dutch Jazz Orch. Strayhorn (Box 40)
      - Ralph La Polla (clarinet) w/ Les Brown (Box 40)
      - Rayner De Michele, All's Well That Ends, 1958 (Box 40)
      - Red Callender Memorial Tribute, Proud Bird, 1992 April 18 (Box 40)
      - Rick Arbuckle, 1980 (Box 40)
      - Roy Porter (Box 40)
      - San Diego (Box 40)
      - San Diego, B. Colette, Cheathams, 1980 (Box 40)
      - San Diego Fl and Harp, Veryle, B.C., Mills (Box 40)
      - San Diego, H. Hoffman and Buddy Collette (Box 40)
      - S. Diego, C. Jackson, B.C., J. Strickman, 1981 (Box 40)
      - "The Sea," P.S. Rose/G. Chase, Tender Understanding Music, ASCAP (Box 40)
      - Seventh Avenue Excerpts (Box 40)
      - Shatara and Stories (Box 40)
      - Side 1: Watts Towers 81, Side 2: Festival B. Collette Big Band (Box 40)
      - Solo Artists Recital - Murphy, Mary Sue Hyatt/Buddy Collette, B. Avramov, 1991 March 1 (Box 40)
      - Speak Out, Collette, Bryant, Scott, 1981 June 28 (Box 40)
      - Spiro Gyro Tape (Box 40)
      - Stan Gilbert - Llew Matthews - Buddy Collette (Box 40)
      - Stan Gilbert - Llew Matthews - Buddy Collette (Box 40)
      - Stan Gilbert - Llew Matthews - Buddy Collette (Box 40)
      - Stars of Swing (Box 40)
      - Susan Peters Harp (Box 40)
      - The Thread Interview, B.C., E. Jones, 1981 October 9 (Box 41)
      - The Thread, Paul Bullock, 1981 (Box 41)
      - The Thread, Buddy Collette and Bruce, 1981 October 23 (Box 41)
      - 3/4 Jazz Band, Buddy Collette, Dir. (Box 41)
      - 3/13 Tape 3 (Box 41)
      - 3/24 I Ran (Box 41)
      - Trauma 1+2 (Box 41)
      - Trauma Tape 3+4 (Box 41)
      - UCI Jazz Festival, UCI Jazz Ensemble, 1994 May 21 (Box 41)
      - [Untitled] (Box 41)
      - [Untitled] (Box 41)
      - [Untitled] (Box 41)
      - [Untitled] (Box 41)
      - [Untitled] (Box 41)
      - [Untitled] (Box 41)
      - [Untitled] (Box 41)
      - [Untitled] (Box 41)
      - [Untitled] (Box 41)
      - [Untitled] (Box 41)
      - [Untitled] (Box 41)
      - [Untitled] (Box 41)
      - [Untitled] (Box 41)
      - Wadsworth Birthday Party, B. Colette, 1995 August 6 (Box 41)
      - Wadsworth Theatre, B.C., Magali, Jazz by the Bay, 1987 September 6 (Box 41)
      - We Are All One People (Box 41)
      - What is (Box 41)
      - Where in the World (Box 41)
      - Woodman Brothers, 1992 August 9 (Box 41)
      - Workshop Concert, 1980 July 26 (Box 41)
      - Yoga and Jazz, J. Stephens, B. Collette - Sam Most, 1974 (Box 41)
    - Sub-Sub-Series 6.2.2: VHS(s)
      VHS recordings documenting performances, interviews, and events.
      CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIOVISUAL: Audiovisual are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email AskLSC@library.ucla.edu.
      - AFI, Clint Eastwood, A&E, 1996 (Box 41)
      - AFI, Clint Eastwood, A&E, 1996 (Box 41)
      - Amazing Teddy Z Party, Ca Deli, 1989 September 18 (Box 41)
      - AT&T B.C. (Box 41)
      - Buddy Collette Birthday, Big Band, Grand Ave Bar, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Buddy Collette Birthday Celebration, Veterans Wadsworth Theatre, 1995 August 6 (Box 41)
      - Buddy Collette, Buckeye Jr. High School, Redding, CA, 1991 September 26 (Box 41)
      - Buddy Collette - Jazz Archive Series - CSU - LA, 2001 (Box 41)
      - Buddy Collette Jazz at Pedrini Music (meet the composers), 1993 March 27 (Box 41)
      - Buddy Collette, John Bolivar, Bob Karr, Tom Shepherd, Gerald Wiggins, Tom Pedrini, 1993 August 21 (Box 41)
      - Buddy Collette, Richard Wyatt Paintings, Central Ave Jazz, 1991 December 17 (Box 41)
      - Buddy Collette, Ron Brown, Tom Shepherd, John Bolivar, Live at Pedrini Music, 1991 November (Box 41)
      - Buddy Collette, Woodman, Britt, Kelson (Box 41)
      - California State University, Dominguez Hills Presents Interdisciplinary Studies 336 "Jazz in the Modern Era" Session Five (5) Dr. Chet Hanley, Instr, 2005 March 1 (Box 41)
      - Central Ave. Live, 1996 July 27-28 (Box 41)
      - Central Ave. Live, 1996 July 27-28 (Box 41)
      - Central Ave. Live, 1996 July 27-28 (Box 41)
      - Central Ave. Live, 1996 July 27-28 (Box 41)
      - Central Avenue Live!, 1996 July 27-28 (Box 41)
      - Central Avenue Live! Rosie Lee Hooks, Producer, Saundra Sharp, Writer/Director, TRT: 58:03, 1996 July 27-28 (Box 41)
      - Charles Mingus, Eric Dolphy (Box 41)
      - Charles Mingus - Triumph of the Underdog (Box 41)
      - Citizen Kane, Orson Welles (Box 41)
      - Club Date - Flute Summit with Buddy Colette (Box 41)
      - Conley Graves Trio, Chico Hamilton Quintet, Anita O'Day, Buddy De Franco, 1956 (Box 41)
      - Conley Graves Trio, Chico Hamilton Quintet, Anita O'Day, Buddy De Franco, 1956 (Box 41)
      - Dead Ringers, Love Gas Station, Buddy Collette (Box 41)
      - DUBS, L.A. Convention and Visitors Bureau, "L.A. Voices," 7:10 mins., Paul Edwards Production Group, 1994 August 2 (Box 41)
      - "Everywhere Show" Garnett Brown and Muse, 1981 August 8 (Box 41)
      - Friends of Buddy Stroke Assoc., 2004-03-14 (Box 41)
      - Garnett Brown "Interface" - CBS-TV, 1981 May 10 (Box 41)
      - The Giving (Box 41)
      - The Glass Wall (Columbia Pictures), Shorty Rogers and his Band, featuring Jack Teagarden, unidentified black combo, possibly including Buddy Collette and Ben Webster, 1953 (Box 42)
      - Jazz America Presentation Video (Box 42)
      - Jazz America Presentation Video (Box 42)
      - Jazz America Presentation Video, Washington Irving Middle School (Box 42)
      - Jazz Camp, Sat Afternoon and Love Tuck, 1986 August 1 (Box 42)
      - Jazz Festival, L.A. High Schools/Performing Tree, 1988 (Box 42)
      - Jazz Interview L.A. Tom Reed, 1987 (Box 42)
      - Jazz Mentorship Program "All That Jazz," Rosie Lee Hooks, Producer, Gail Choice, Producer/Director, TRT: 28:31 (Box 42)
      - Jazz'n America, Buddy Collette Quintet, L.A. Southwest College, Michael Pitts Prod., 1991 January 26 (Box 42)
      - Jazz'n America, Buddy Collette Quintet, L.A. Southwest College, Michael Pitts Producer, 1991 January 26 (Box 42)
      - Jazz'n America, Buddy Collette Quintet w. F. Katz, L.A. Southwest College, Michael Pitts Prod., 1991 January 26 (Box 42)
      - Jazz'N America, 1991 January 26 (Box 42)
      - Jeffery Plansker, Director, Lotus, "This is Notes" :30 (Box 42)
      - Kaiser Permanente, "Dr. Sweet," TV:30, 2-track stereo, DUB, 1995 August 10 (Box 42)
      - KCET Grandpa (Box 42)
      - Kennedy Center Awards, B. Carter, 1996 (Box 42)
      - LA Arts Mix #4, Buddy Collette History (Box 42)
      - LA Arts Variety Show, Care-A-Van *Tape #2, TRT: 01:08:43 (Box 42)
      - L.A.C.E.S. Music Dept., presents Spring Concert, Jazz Ensemble, 1997 (Box 42)
      - L.A. City Council Meeting, Buddy Collette Presentation, 1995 September 8 (Box 42)
      - L.A. City Council Meeting, Buddy Collette Presentation, 1995 September 8 (Box 42)
      - Life and Times, Buddy Collette and Others (Box 42)
      - Life and Times - Buddy Collette et al., KCET - TV, 1996 May (Box 42)
      - Life and Times Buddy Collette, (Thursday Studio), 1994 November 24 (Box 42)
      - Marriage of Mariamu, 36:00, Sharing is Unity, 22:00 (Box 42)
      - Mayor Riordan, American Jazz Masters (Box 42)
      - Midday Sunday, "Buddy Collette/Jazz America," VTR#, 2005 July 31 (Box 42)
      - Midday Sunday, Rhythms of L.A., 2004 September 5 (Box 42)
      - Mosaic #4, Buddy Collette and Al Williams, 1997 October (Box 42)
      - "Mr. R.P. the Career," 5 Minutes, Mr. R.R. Cline, Black Note, 1992 (Box 42)
      - Musicians Network Showcase (Box 42)
      - On Any Day: A Visit to Four L.A. Neighborhoods, THX 2 B.C. and MCU, 1993 (Box 42)
      - The Percy Faith Orchestra Japan Tour '90, Recorded Live at Omiya Sonic City Hall, Tokyo, 1990 June 19 (Box 42)
      - Percy Faith Orchestra, Japan Tour - Alan Broadbent - Conductor, (simulated stereo-HiFi), 1956 (Box 42)
      - A Promise Delivered Buddy Collette, 1990 September (Box 42)
      - Reunion, C. Hamilton, B. Collette, F. Katz, 1975 (Box 42)
      - Roy Eldridge and Buddy Eldridge (Box 42)
      - The Search for Central Avenue, 2:45, Directed by: Jan D. Arnold, Featuring: Roy Porter, Clora Bryant, Buddy Collette, 1996 (Box 43)
      - Shotgun Freeway Drives thru L.A., a documentary film by Morgan Neville and Harry Pallenberg (Box 43)
      - Shotgun Freeway featuring Buddy Collette (Box 43)
      - Summer Sounds PSA Buddy Collette :15 and :30, 1996 (Box 43)
      - Talking with Buddy Collette, Part I, 1996 February 26 (Box 43)
      - The Today Show L.A., Olvera St, 1990 March 23 (Box 43)
      - 2. Olympics, 1988 (Box 43)
      - [Untitled] (Box 43)
      - [Untitled] (Box 43)
      - Verona Italy, Buddy Collette/James Newton, 1988 (Box 43)
      - Watts Festival, Two in the Town, Buddy Collette Quintet, 1985 (Box 43)
      - We Are All One People (Box 43)
      - Werner Chepelsky Last Dance, :30, Buddy Collette, Landmark Bank, 1989 June 30 (Box 43)
      - William "Buddy" Collette QT., Club Date Elario's - San Diego, 1990 (Box 43)
    - Sub-Sub-Series 6.2.3: VHS-C(s)
      VHS-C recordings documenting performances, interviews, and events.
      - Jazz Camp, 1987 (Box 43)
      - Japan, 1986 (Box 43)
  - Sub-Series 6.3: Digital Media (Physical Carriers)
    CDs, DVDs, and DATs documenting performances, interviews, and reference recordings.
    CONTAINS UNPROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Digital materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email AskLSC@library.ucla.edu.
    - Sub-Sub-Series 6.3.1: CD(s)
      Digital recordings on CDs (physical carriers).
      - Anthony Ortega on Evidence, Recorded in Paris, France, 1992 (Box 43)
      - Buddy Collette Holiday Triangle, 6 Tracks (Box 43)
      - Film Music Themes - Volume 1, Composed by Eric Butler (213) 380 3900, 2006 (Box 43)
      - Frank Adams Birmingham Heritage Band (Box 43)
      - Gail and Doug's 50th Mix (Box 43)
      - Jazz America Class of 2005 (Box 43)
      - Live your life with Verve summer groove, 2006 (Box 43)
      - Montell Jordan, "this is how we do it", 1995 (Box 43)
      - Not BC Music (Box 43)
      - NPR Jazz Profiles, NEA Jazz Master Jim Hall, copyright, 2005 (Box 43)
      - Tevin Campbell, "I'm Ready" (Box 43)
      - Thank You Jazz America, From Garrett Mingus, The Best of the Gipsy Kings, 1995 (Box 43)
      - 12 Tone Blues, B.C. (Box 43)
      - Washington Prep Jazz Ensemble, Thank You, Buddy (Box 43)
      - A Windham Wonderland (Box 43)
    - Sub-Sub-Series 6.3.2: DVD(s)
      Digital recordings on DVDs (physical carriers).
      - Armstrong, Hines, Jazz Casual (Box 43)
      - Charles Lloyd, Billy Higgins, HOME, Edited version 23 m. rt (Box 43)
      - El Sistema, 60 Minutes Segment, Aired April 16, 2008 (Box 43)
      - Jump In - The Four Toppers accompanied by Cee Pee Johnson and his orchestra, I've Got My Fingers Crossed, Fats Waller, 1935; 1941 (Box 43)
      - KSCS Prod. A Night At El Camino, Catalina Bar and Grill, 2006 May 28 (Box 43)
      - Pro Drum XMAS, 2007 (Box 43)
    - Sub-Sub-Series 6.3.3: DAT(s)
      Ditigal recordings on DATs (physical carriers).
      - Buddy Collette Big Band, Master, 1995 May 19 (Box 43)
      - Doug Botnick (Box 43)
      - [Untitled] (Box 43)